Charles A. and June R. P. Ross Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
- Locality Information, Series I
  - Maps., 002879
    - Map. USGS 7.5' topographic quadrangle - Schroeder Mtn., Nevada - Idaho. Scale 1:24000. Annotated with localities including PN-4193p and PN-4196p., 1968; 002983
    - Map. USGS 7.5' topographic quadrangle - Swales Mountain, Nevada - Elko Co. Scale 1:24000. Annotated with localities including PN-4198f and PN-4199p., 1968; 002984
    - Map. USGS 7.5' topographic quadrangle - Swales Mountain NW, Nevada - Elko Co. Scale 1:24000. Annotated with localities including PN-4197f., 1968; 002985
    - Map. USGS 7.5' topographic quadrangle - Wells, Nevada. Scale 1:24000. Annotated with localities including PN-4168-F thru PN-4171-F., 1968; 002989
    - Map. USGS 7.5' topographic quadrangle - Ungina Wongo, Nevada. Scale 1:24000. Annotated with localities including PN-4181p and PN-4183p., 1970; 002988
    - Map. USGS 7.5' topographic quadrangle - Coal Mine Basin, Nevada. Scale 1:24000. Two copies annotated with localities including PN-4001-F, PN-4002-F, PN-4178 and localities 3C thru 3J, 2T and 2U. One copy has been partially mapped with formational contacts and faults., 1971; 002957
    - Map. USGS 7.5' topographic quadrangle - The Buttes, Nevada. Scale 1:24000. Some volcanics are mapped. No annotated localities., 1971; 002986
    - Map. USGS 7.5' topographic quadrangle - The Narrows, Nevada. Scale 1:24000. Two copies annotated with localities including PN-4000-F and PN-4177, R-3A-OR, R-3B-F, R-3C-F and R-3D-OR., 1972; 002987
    - Map. USGS Index to Topographic Maps of Nevada. Annotated with localities where measured sections were generated by [R.E.] Grant and [G.] Steele in 1959., 1979; 002995
    - Map. USGS Index to Topographic Maps of Nevada. Annotated with checkmarks indicating maps later obtained by C.A. Ross associated with his work during and after Chevron Corp.'s Roberts Mountain project [NV]. Not annotated with localities., 1979; 002996
    - Map. Joint Venture between Wilde, Inc. and TerraScan Group, Inc. - Arizona-New Mexico Geologic and Photogrologic Compilation Map - Scale 1:250000. Not annotated with localities., 1982; 002851
    - Map. USGS 2 x 1 degree topographic quadrangle - Fort Stockton, Texas. Scale 1:250000. 1955-1956 edition; photocopy of original. Annotated with localities and measured section positions, as well as traced road routes to and from the respective localities., 003052
    - Map. Three blank quadrangle map order forms for Arizona (Index June 1963), one topographic map symbol sheet (from Apr 1962) and photocopies of two quarters of two separate USGS 15' topographic maps (Holy Joe Peak, NW1/4 - Scale 1:62500 - Datum NAD27 - Contains Section 16 of Ross (1973) penciled in; Benson, SW1/4 - Scale 1:62500 - Datum NAD27. No locality information provided)., 002837
    - Map. 1962-1975 - USGS 7.5' topographic quadrangle - Kittridge Springs Quadrangle, Nevada. Scale 1:24000. Annotated with formational contacts, structures, map symbology (e.g., strike and dip) and is partially colored. Not annotated with localities, 003166
    - Map. USGS Physiographic Map of the state of Arizona - United States. Scale 1:500000. Not annotated with localities., 002873
    - Map. 1980 - USGS Geologic Map of Northern Independence Mts, Elko County, Nevada. Scale ~1:170,000. Two copies, both of which are not annotated with localities., 003167
    - Map. 1980-1989. Roadmap of Nevada, produced by H.M. Gousha Co. (on behalf of Chevron). Scale: 1 in: 40 km. Annotated with localities (not numbered)., 002948
    - Maps. One map of Coronado National Forest (USDA Forest Service-SW Region map, 1963) and another map of the state of Arizona labeled "localities." The map labeled "localities" has the map scale and presumed area containing localities physically cut out of the map; neither of the two maps is annotated with localities., 1963-1965; 003002
    - Maps. Thirty-four [37] USGS 7.5' and 15' quadrangle topographic maps from Nevada fitted to 18" x 24" size, each given an enclosure name A-1 thru A-37, with subtitles "Fossil Location Map, Roberts Mountains Project Area." These maps were part of the investigation headed by C.A. Ross on behalf of Chevron Corp. between 1980-1985., 002992
    - Maps. Mapping and Charting Establishment of the Canada Department of Defence 15' topographic quadrangle - Nakina, British Columbia, Canada [Map 104 N/2 E] - 1954 version, printed 1967. Scale 1:50000. Two copies, one annotated with sections labeled A, B and C and the other annotated with specimen localities., 003016
    - Study Area Map. 1992 - Map of Study Areas plotted and printed by Gulf Oil Exploration and Production Company for the Humboldt, Nevada area. Scale 1:500,000. Not annotated with localities., 003174
    - Study Area Map. 1992 - Map of Study Areas plotted and printed by Gulf Oil Exploration and Production Company for the Salt Lake Desert, Utah area. Scale 1:500,000. Not annotated with localities., 003175
    - Topographic Map. USGS 7.5' topographic quadrangle - Glass Mountain Ranch, Texas Scale: 1:24000. Annotated with some pencil marks (formational contacts) and at least one locality (unnumbered)., 1983; 003064
    - Topographic Map. USGS 15' topographic quadrangle - Hess Canyon, Texas. 1923 Edition. Reprinted 1946. Scale: 1:62500. Annotated with stratigraphic sections and strike and dip measurements; section numbers on map match section numbers recorded in Ross' 1957 field notebooks (see Association Tab); note on upper right map corner states "Map of Charles A. Ross -- Letter dated June 17, 1957 To M.I.O., U.S.G.S.", 003119
    - Topographic Map. Composite topographic map (composed of xeroxed sheets of a large (2x1 USGS topographic quadrangle?) spanning the majority of Presidio County, Texas and parts of Hudspeth and Jeff Davis counties. Annotations include highlights and circled areas of interest (mostlyPermian strata), after areas visited by P.B. King (1937). Scale: 1:250000. Not annotated with localities., 003059
    - Topographic and Geologic Index Maps. Topographic index maps for California (Feb 1979), Colorado (Feb 1980), Idaho (Nov 1966), Montana (Feb 1980), New Mexico (Feb 1980), Oregon (May 1980) and Wyoming (Jan 1980); Geologic Map indicies for Arizona (1975 edition; reprinted 1983), Idaho (1975 edition; reprinted 1983) and Texas (reprinted 1983)., 002838
    - Topographic and Geologic Index Maps. 1979-1983. Topographic index maps for Utah (2 copies, one of which has Grant Steele measured section and examined/partial measured section localities; May 1980) and Nevada (Apr 1979); one copy of a geologic map index of Nevada (1976 version, reprinted 1983); one plastic overlay--variable scale for locating minutes and seconds of arc on 7.5' and 15' topographic maps., 003177
  - Petrophysical Data., 003020
    - Core Description/Interpretation. Charles A. Ross - 1944-1955 - Issued to Forest Oil Co. by Permian Basin Sample Laboratory - Sampled Interval: 144-12096' - Completion Date: 1 Jan 1955 - Completed by: Phillips Petroleum Co. - Lease: Elsinore - Well Name: Elsinore #1 - Well Location: Section 53, Block D, GC&SF Survey, Pecos County, Texas - TD: 12096'; Elev: 4105' [=KB]; accompanying paleontological report by R.V. Hollingsworth, detailing paleo findings for samples examined between 144-12080'., 003034
    - Core Description/Interpretation. Charles A. Ross - 1951-1955 - Issued to Forest Oil Co. by Permian Basin Sample Laboratory - Sampled Interval: 2000' - 18673 ' - Completion Date: 1 Jan 1955 - Completed by: Hunt Oil Co. - Lease: Elsinore Royalty Co. - Well Name: Elsinore Royalty Co. #47 - Well Location: Section 21, Block B, GC&SF Survey, Pecos County, Texas - TD: 18673'; Elev: 3741' [=KB]; accompanying paleontological report by R.V. Hollingsworth, detailing paleo findings for samples examined between 5000-18504'., 003033
    - Core Description/Interpretation. Charles A. Ross - 1955-1956 - Litholog - Logged interval: Surface -17252' - Spud: 11 Jul 1955 - Completed By: Hunt Oil Co. & Gulf Oil Co. [JV]. - Field: [Elsinore Multipay] - Well Name: Elsinore Royalty Co. #48 - Location: Section 51, Block D, GC&SF Survey, Pecos County, Texas - TD: 17252' - Elev: 4051'; one copy of a report by R.V. Hollingsworth the Paleontological Laboratory on Elsinore Royalty Co. #48, including paleontological and lithology notes from intervals 1450-14400' and 16500-16750'., 003031
    - Core Description/Interpretation. Charles A. Ross - 1956 - Issued to Forest Oil Co. by Permian Basin Sample Laboratory - Surface - 17000' - Completion Date: 6 Dec 1956 - Completed by: Hunt Oil Co. - Lease: Elsinore Royalty Co. - Well Name: Elsinore Royalty Co. #51 - Well Location: Section 65, Block D, GC&SF Survey, Pecos County, Texas - TD: 17000'; no KB, Elev, DF or GL data provided., 003032
    - Core Description/Interpretation. Charles A. Ross - 1986 - Core descriptions for two cored intervals (7980-8306 ft and 8395-8496 ft) for well HSA 1392-P - Field: Wagon Wheel - Well Name: HSA 1392-P - Location: Sec. 4, Block O, G. & M.M.B. & A. Survey, Ward County, Texas, 003029
    - Core Description/Interpretation. Charles A. Ross - No Date Given - Issued to Forest Oil Co. by Permian Basin Sample Laboratory - Sampled Interval: 50-13980' - Completed by: Fred Turner Jr [Oil/Prod Co.]. - Lease: G.C. Combs - Well Name: G.C. Combs #1 - Well Location: Section 37, Block 21, GC&SF Survey, Brewster County, Texas - TD: 13980', 003036
    - Core Description/Interpretation. Charles A. Ross - No Date Given - Interpretation by C.A. Ross (Biostrat CXAB01) - Analyzed Interval: 5450-5550' [partial] - Completions: N/A - Lease: N/A - Well Name: Mullin #2 - Well Location: Section 149, Block 8-5, D&PRR Survey, Motley County, Texas - TD: N/A, 003130
    - Core Description. Charles A. Ross - One partial, generalized stratigraphic column photocopy compiled from Chevron's Mullin #1 well sourced by data from two cores - Location: Sec. 149, Block S-5, Motley County, Texas; this copy might be related to a publication (internal or otherwise)., 003027
    - Well Log & Core Description/Interpretation. Charles A. Ross - 1961 - Issued to Forest Oil Co. by Permian Basin Sample Laboratory - Log Type: Gamma Ray and Neutron Porosity - Logged Interval: 0-9865' - Completion Date: 8 Jun 1961 - Completed by: Forest Oil Co. & Lone Star Production Co. [JV]. - Field: Wildcat - Well Name: Jo Anne Moore #1 - Well Location: Section 7, Block 1, GC&SF Survey, Pecos County, Texas - TD: 9865' - KB: 4418' - DF: 4416' - GL: 4406 - Elev: 4416'; accompanying mudlogging report from Geolog, Inc., 003035
    - Well Log & Core Description/Interpretation. Charles A. Ross - 1977-1990 - Reproduced by Electrical Log Services, Midland, Texas - API: 42-371-31748 - Gamma Ray and Resistivity - Logged interval: 4840'-13476' - Completed By: Texas Pacific Oil Co. - Field: Elsinore Multipay - Well Name: Montgomery Fulk #9 - Location: Section 9, Block 170, Pecos County, Texas - TD: 13478' - KB: 4258' - DF: 4257' - GL: 4241'; two copies of core description: one on well log, the other a typewritten copy. Core description has accompanying interpretation on well log copy (facies, structures, formational members, etc.)., 003030
    - Well Log & Core Description/Interpretation. Charles A. Ross - 1980-1990 - Completion by Sun Oil [Texas Pacific Oil Company] on May 18, 1980 - Logged by C.A. Ross in March 1990 - Field: Wildcat - Well Name: Madre Grande #1 - Location: Sec. 59, Block 331 [NE Brewster County, very close to Pecos County; see Associations Tab] - Township: T.C. Roberts Original Grant - KB: 5166' - DF: 5164' - GL: 5134' - TD: 20100', 003021
    - Well Log & Core Description. Charles A. Ross - 1952-1954 - Reproduction by West Texas Electrical Log Service - One run of Gamma Ray/Neutron Density, reported by The Western Company - Completions by Slick-Urschel [1952-1954] - Field: Wildcat - Well Name: Decie #1 - Location: Sec. 47, Block 4 [660' FNL, 2310' FEL; see Associations tab], Brewster County, Texas - Datum [Elev]: 4446' - TD: 9741' - KB, DF and/or GL not provided [surface pad/derricks?]; one copy of a core description by Waring Bradley and Murchison, originally sold to Forest Oil Corp. by the Permian Basin Sample Laboratory, Midland, Texas, annotated with handwritten notes by C.A. Ross; one paleontological report (15 Nov 1953) by R.V. Hollingsworth., 003025
    - Well Log & Core Description. Charles A. Ross - 1955-1956 - Reproduction by West Texas Electrical Log Service; two copies, logging two runs (one shallow, one deep) of Gamma Ray and Neutron Porosity, by Schumberger Well Surveying Corp. Completion date: 29 Jun 1956 - Gulf Oil Corp. [7 Oct 1955 and 29 Jun 1956] - Field: Wildcat - Well Name: D.S. Combs #1 - Location: Sec. 5 [Sec. 16 according to paleontology report], Block 4 [see Associations tab], Brewster County, Texas - KB: 4114' - DF: 4115' - GL: 4102' - TD: 516'/9500'; one copy of a core description by A.R. Murchison, originally sold to Forest Oil Corp. by the Permian Basin Sample Laboratory, Midland, Texas, unannotated with handwritten notes by C.A. Ross; a paleontological report on the core, completed by R.V. Hollingsworth 15 Dec 1956., 003026
  - Stratigraphic Sections., 002751
    - Locality Information and Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - 1965-1968 - Field notes, measured sections and specimen photography from various sections published in Ross (1973). Although the paper includes 38 sections from SE Arizona, this archive includes information for 28 of 38 of the sections, including the Fossil Creek [Section 1], Pine [Section 2], East Verde River [Section 3], Schoolhouse Tank [Section 4], Tonto Creek [Section 5], Christopher Creek [Section 6 (referred to as section 5 1/2)], Big Spring Canyon [Section 7], Oak Creek Road [Ranch; Section 8], Roach Wash or "Galiuro" Limestone [Section 15], Eskiminzin Wash [Section 16], Coolidge Dam [Section 17], Gila Mountains [Calva; Section 18], Clifton or Tule Spring Limestone [Section 19], Vekol Mts. [Section 20], Waterman Mountains [Section 21], Twin Peaks [Section 22], Johnny Lyon Hills [Section 23], Gunnison Hills [Sections 24a and 24b], Portal [Section 29], Dry Canyon [Sections 30 and 31], Horquilla Peak [Section 32], Earp Hill [Section 33], Pridham Creek [N. Squaretop, 002765
    - Locality Information. Charles A. Ross - Topographic maps containing stratigraphic section localities for C.A. Ross' 1973 publication in AAPG Bulletin, from SE Arizona. Index maps (from the USGS) are included and annotated (noting all topographic maps, both marked and unmarked, purchased and owned by C.A. Ross). Stratigraphic section localities within this archive from Ross (1973) include the following; [Note: Format - Section #: Section name from publication (QUADRANGLE NAME; # minutes/degrees)]; Section 1: Fossil Creek (Turret Peak Quadrangle; 15 minute); Section 2: Pine (Pine Quadrangle; 15 minute); Section 3: East Verde River (Pine Quadrangle; 15 minute); Section 4: Schoolhouse Tank (Promontory Butte; 15 minute); Section 5: Tonto Creek (Promontory Butte; 15 minute); Section 6: Christopher Creek (Promontory Butte; 15 minute); Section 7: Big Spring Canyon (Chediski Peak; 15 minute); Section 8: Oak Creek Road [Ranch] (Chediski Peak; 15 minute); Section 13: Superior (Superior; 15 minute); Section 14: Winkelman, 1929-Oct 1964; 002763
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - Original (hand drawn), xeroxed and copied stratigraphic sections with accompanying sample localities labeled, from C.A. Ross' 1973 publication in AAPG Bulletin (with scales varying from 1" = 50' to 1" = 20'; handwritten legend included). Laminated, miniature prints of stratigraphic sections [for vellum mounting?]; sample collection list (original; handwritten by C.A. Ross) for sections 23 thru 29 of Ross (1973); organized list of all sample collection localities for sections measured in SE Arizona from Ross (1973), tied to previously unlabeled stratigraphic columns; verified locality list for sections connected to Ross 1973 (copy of publication)., 17 Jun 1965-05 Sep 1966; 002764
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1959 - Two typewritten copies of stratigraphy notes (measured sections #1, 2, 2A, 3, 4, .5 mi E of 4, 4A, 5, Jail Canyon, 5A, Clay Slide, 6, 6A, 6B, 6C, 7, 7A and from miscellaneous collections) of C.A. Ross in the Glass Mountains, W. Texas; two typed copies of Ross sections 1, 2, 3 and 4; two typed copies of King's section 27; reference list compiled for Ross and Ross depositional sequences paper along with a section immediately following the references, named "Explanation of Figures" (figure captions?)., 002913
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - 1999 - Workbook of stratigraphic sections from C. Ross, J. Udden and P. King (Glass Mountains, W. Texas), R. Moore, D. Boardman and S. Mazzullo (Kansas), and T. Williams (Hueco Mts.)., 003096
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - Miscellaneous measured sections, sample locality notes and specimen photography from Arizona and New Mexico. This includes sections which were measured, re-measured or manually duplicated (e.g., hand-drawn) by C.A. Ross and derived from various published and unpublished sources., 002779
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Hand-drawn measured sections and stratigraphy notes from Wanless' Harquahala Mine section; typewritten and xeroxed field notes on two sections measured near Harquahala Mine, La Paz County, Arizona (pages H-1 thru H-7), with some notes by C.A. Ross. Originally included in box with documents related to Charles A. Ross' AAPG Bulletin paper (1973)., 002768
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross and Floyd F. Sabins - 1965 - Stratigraphic columns, field notes, locality information, sample descriptions and specimen photography from three sections (Dos Cabezas, Blue Mountain, Portal) published in Ross and Sabins (1965) and Ross (1973). Each of the three sections is stored in a separate archival envelope (12" x 9"); Xeroxed copies of field notes for Dos Cabezas and Blue Mountain sections., 002767
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - Hand drawn and xeroxed copies of stratigraphic column drafts of C.A. Ross' Leonard-Word sections 1, 2, 2A, 3, 4, 4A, 5, 5A, 6, 6A, 6B, 6C, 7, 7A, 7B and the Jail Canyon, Clay Slide [Udden] sections of the Glass Mountains, Pecos/Brewster county, Texas; section 6 is remeasured from P.B. King's section 12., 003071
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - Hand drawn, xeroxed and vellum copies of stratigraphic columns by C.A. Ross in efforts towards remeasuring sections by P.B. King. Sections measured in the Glass Mountains, Pecos/Brewster county, Texas area include 5, 6, 7, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28; some published clippings of section 8 and 9., 003072
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1995 - Handdrawn stratigraphic sections by C.A. Ross; sections 1-10 of Ross (1963), titled "Standard Wolfcampian Series"; one section from both J. Udden and P.B. King, (both redrawn by C.A. Ross); redrawn stratigraphic columns produced from Lenox Hills sections originally measured by Ross (likely reported in Ross, 1963; see Associations Tab)., 003116
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1995 - Handdrawn and photo copies of stratigraphic sections by C.A. Ross; sections 11-20 of Ross (1963), titled "Standard Wolfcampian Series"; some handdrawn stratigraphic correlations of sections are included., 003118
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1995 - Handdrawn and photo copies of stratigraphic sections by C.A. Ross; sections #21-30 of Ross (1963), titled "Standard Wolfcampian Series"; some handdrawn stratigraphic correlations of sections and eustasy curves are included; handdrawn depictions of stratigraphic sections in hillside (including Uddenites Zone, Sections I, II, III, IV, V, VI, 7 and 7 (cont); photo and handdrawn copies of King sections 22-27., 003122
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1995 - Handdrawn and photo copies of stratigraphic sections by C.A. Ross; sections #33-42 of Ross (1963), titled "Standard Wolfcampian Series"; some handdrawn stratigraphic correlations of sections and eustasy curves are included, 003124
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - 1957-2000 - Photocopies of some sections measured by P.B. King (1930), redrawn by C.A. Ross (ca. 1957) and handdrawn partial replicates of stratigraphic sections by C.A. Ross (ca. 1999-2000), originally measured by P.B. King in 1930; these sections were mesaured in roughly the same region as C.A. Ross measured his sections #1 through #10 (published in GSA Memoir 88, "Standard Wolfcampian Series."), 003114
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - Hand drawn, xeroxed and vellum copies of stratigraphic column drafts of miscellaneous sections generated by C.A. Ross in the Glass Mountains, Pecos/Brewster county, Texas area., 003073
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - Winkleman Section (13 (14?)). July 5-6, 1965. Locality information for 7-5-65 M thru AG and 7-6-65-A thru D. Hand drawn stratigraphic sections, specimen photography (fusulinids and other invertebrates), xeroxed and retyped copies of field notes from C.A. Ross., 002752
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - Black River Canyon Section (11 (12?)). June 24, 1965. Locality information for 6-24-65-M thru X. Hand drawn stratigraphic sections, specimen photography (fusulinids and other invertebrates), xeroxed and retyped copies of field notes from H.R. Wanless., 002755
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - White River Bridge (White River Canyon) Section (10 (11?)). June 25, 1965. Locality information for 6-25-65-A thru K. Hand drawn stratigraphic sections, specimen photography (fusulinids and other invertebrates), xeroxed and retyped copies of field notes from H.R. Wanless and C.A. Ross., 002756
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - Carrizo Creek (Bridge) Section (9 (10?)). June 20, 1965. Locality information for 6-20-65-A thru G. Hand drawn stratigraphic sections, specimen photography (fusulinids and other invertebrates), handwritten and xeroxed field notes from C.A. Ross., 002757
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - Salt River Section (9 (10?)). June 21, June 23 and June 24, 1965. Locality information for 6-21-65-A thru U; 6-23-65-A thru J; 6-24-65-A thru E. Hand drawn stratigraphic sections, specimen photography (fusulinids and other invertebrates), personal and xeroxed field notes from C.A. Ross, personal, xeroxed and retyped field notes from H.R. Wanless., 002758
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - Superior Section (12 (13?)). July 1, 1965, March 19, 1968 and September 4, 1966. Locality information for 7-1-65-A thru 7-1-65-X, 9-4-66-C and 3-19-68-A. Hand drawn stratigraphic sections, specimen photography (fusulinids and other invertebrates), xeroxed and retyped copies of field notes from C.A. Ross and H.R. Wanless., 002754